Guide to the Eastern Washington Historical Media Collection 1928-1987
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Eastern Washington Historical Media Collection
1928-1987
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
SC 013
1 linear foot of shelf space 1 box
The Eastern Washington Historical Media collection contains audio and video documenting eastern Washington state life, primarily focusing on farming.
The majority of south-eastern Washington state was settled in the 1870s, and the most common industry was farming, primarily wheat.
The Eastern Washington Historical Media collection contains audio and video documenting eastern Washington state life, primarily focusing on farming.
Due to the diverse formats and odd sizes and shapes, organization of the materials is solely so as to allow them to fit within their box. In general, multiple iterations of the same (or similar) items are placed next to each other.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection was created from a number of small accessions, some numbered but many unprocessed. These include MS1993-46, MS2002-15, and an item from UPC-7.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington (State), Eastern -- History
Agriculture -- Washington (State)
Agriculture; Washington (State); Moving Images
- Davis Way Dedication. Audio: 5 LPs; 1 cassette., 1950 (Box 1, Item 1)
- To Till A Field: Man and Machine on the Palouse. Edited master. 12:25 3/4" U-matic video., 9/28/1987 (Box 1, Item 2)
- To Till A Field: Man and Machine on the Palouse. 12:25 3/4" U-matic video., 1986 (Box 1, Item 3)
- Keith Williams "To Till a Field" and "People and the Plow." VHS., 1987 (Box 1, Item 4)
- People and the Plow: Who Reaps the Harvest WSU Exhibit guide. Paper., 1987 (Box 1, Item 5)
- Palouse Past WSU Reader's Theatre on case and tape. 53 min. 3/4" U-matic video., 6/16/1980 (Box 1, Item 6)
- Leonard Young--horse-drawn combine - Young filmed horse-drawn combine on Harold Brewer farm in Whitman County. Formerly IMS video 10161 but removed from circulation due to damage in Sept. 2005. This U-matic tape has been repaired but must be rewound with great care. A copy is in current catalog as VHS 12623. 16 min. 3/4" U-matic video., 1935 circa (Box 1, Item 7)
- Leonard Young--horse-drawn combine - Young filmed horse-drawn combine on Harold Brewer farm in Whitman County. Copied from damaged U-matic (item 7) in Sept 2005. 16 min. VHS., 1935 circa (Box 1, Item 8)
- Norman Longhurst film of Mayview tramway and Garfield County farming. 15 min. 16 mm. film., 1935 circa (Box 1, Item 9)
- Norman Longhurst - farming, horse-harvest, Mayview train, hog butchering, sausage making. VHS., 1935 circa (Box 1, Item 10)
- Gilleland Historical Films (Master) on IMS label with "Historical Master" and handwritten "1929-WSC." Primarily life on Washington State College campus and in the city of Pullman. VHS., 1927-1929 (Box 1, Item 11)
- Combines, Whitman Co. Work film for "This is WSC." VHS., 1950 circa (Box 1, Item 12)
- War Construction in the Desert: construction of Hanford, 1943-1944. 103 min. VHS., 1944 (Box 1, Item 13)
- Reedited: "War Construction in the Desert:" construction of Hanford, 1943-1944. Incorporates sound from item (13) above and video form an original silent VHS copy held at WSU Tri-Cities. DVD., 1944 (Box 1, Item 14)
- Gilleland Historical Films. Primarily life on Washington State College campus and in the city of Pullman. 2 reels 16mm film., 1927-1929 (Box 1, Item 15-16)
- C.E. Graves Historical Films. Primarily life in the city of Pullman; also greater Palouse and the Wallowas. Ca. 1927-1940s. 3 reels 16mm film., 1927-1940 (Box 1, Item 17-19 (o.s.))